BRANDON "BEE" SCHMERSAL

brandonschmersal@gmail.com | 412-251-8012 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/brandonschmersal/ Pittsburgh, PA | portfolio: https://bee.surf | github: https://github.com/bee-dmg

END USER SUPPORT ANALYST

Experienced professional with proven success in diverse business environments. Strong ability to manage projects from concept to completion ensuring on-time, on-budget, and on-target results. Demonstrated skills at creating and executing processes and procedures that enhance operational efficiencies. Equally adept at working on teams and individually with minimal supervision.

KEY PROFICIENCIES

Technical: PowerShell, O365 Exchange Server, Azure, Auto Hotkey, SQL, JavaScript, React,

HTML, Bootstrap, CSS, Node.js, Express, MongoDB

Other: Full-Cycle Project Management, Strategic Planning and Implementation, Training and

Development, Process Improvements, End User Relationships

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SOUNDSTACK 2022-PRESENT

CUSTOMER SUPPORT SPECIALIST

Support the front lines for internal and external customers. Use encoding tools and software to ensure media is the correct bitrate. Add to internal wiki. Intake and resolve incoming tickets. Troubleshoot encoding and audio issues.

ARMADA SUPPLY CHAIN SOLUTIONS, PITTSBURGH, PA

2019-2022

END USER SUPPORT ANALYST

Support Level 1 and 2 software and hardware needs for more than 400 users. Administer Active Directory and O365. Develop base images for deployment. Migrate Windows 7 to Windows 10 including configuring MDT server and creating images. Investigate and resolve problems and arrange for new hardware. Streamline PC configurations. Orient new hires. Design batch files. Note and address security risks and patches with end users. Switched phones from Avaya to Zoom. Established policies in a Secure Web Gateway, Netskope. Helped construct and manage SharePoint environment. Teach end users how to utilize Sharepoint, Teams, Zoom, and O365. Contributed to internal documentation with technical documentation. Install and troubleshoot network printers. Study documentation to expand security and ease of administration.

 Simplified imaging process to save about three hours on each of 100 computers per year and increase productivity by 20 hours weekly.

CLOCKWISE, PITTSBURGH, PA

2015-2021

BILLING SUPPORT SPECIALIST (2018-2021)

Administered and utilized application billing clients for cost of goods and services. Collaborated with small team continuously simplify existing systems.

Found multiple billing errors saving \$20K-\$30K of missed revenue yearly.

FLOOR MANAGER (2017-2018)

Educated and mentored new staff on safety and development. Served as technical support specialist for multiple operations. Arranged supplies and facilitated shipping and logistics. Prepared image files and operated DTG printers. Spearheaded production and distribution throughout ink, screen, and receiving department. Delivered products to local clients. Liaised with staff to complete orders within tight deadlines and proper resources.

 Streamlined shipping processes and worked with carriers to decrease shipping costs by more than \$20K by utilizing bulk international shipping service.

INVENTORY MANAGER (2015-2017)

Devised billing application for on-demand services. Serviced all fulfillment and print-on demand clients. Employed multiple web applications to seamlessly integrate clients into Clockwise's environment and solve all related issues.

- Learned multiple software including Shopify, Skuvault, and Shipstation.
- Provided weekly reports to founder containing information on sales and client revenue.

R1 RCM, PITTSBURGH, PA

2018-2019

SUPPORT CENTER TECHNICIAN

Served customers and assisted internal personnel and external clients by telephone. Provided routine Tier 1 troubleshooting and product support including studying logs for errors. Aided hardware needs for external clients including imaging machines and provided hardware to clients meeting SLA guidelines. Tested products and proprietary applications to understand functionality. Escalated issues to Tier 3 when necessary to work with development to resolve. Scripted Auto Hot Key to simplify account creation and access. Queried and approved user access via SQL. Trained new Tier 1 and Tier 2 personnel.

 Contributed to internal Wikipedia saving technicians potentially 3-6 hours of time by automating permissions granting to account through GUI and developing batch files to further streamline productivity.

WHOLE FOODS MARKET PITTSBURGH. PA

2011-2015

OVERNIGHT STOCKER (2011-2012); FROZEN SPECIALIST/BUYER (2012-2015)

Ordered and stocked product for two departments producing \$80K in weekly revenue. Supervised 10 colleagues each shift. Built displays complying with company standards. Trained team members.

- Attended and completed Assistant Team Leader Training Program.
- Achieved multiple team member of month awards and constantly stocked 70 cases of product hourly.

CALIFORNIA UNIVERSITY OF PENNSYLVANIA, CALIFORNIA, PA COMPUTER TECHNICIAN

2008-2011

Addressed technical difficulties for faculty and students. Moved college PCs to new domain. Taught students and colleagues on virus removal, email configuration on mobile devices, basic troubleshooting, etc.

- Supervised print lab operations and facility.
- Provided technical support to entire campus with Desktop Support Technician.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Graphic Design

California University of Pennsylvania, California, PA, 2011

Professional Training

Full Stack Web and Mobile Development, Full Stack Web and Mobile Development Bootcamp, 2021-Present

Licenses & Certifications

Google IT Automation Professional Certificate, Google via Coursera, November 2020 Getting Started with Azure, LearnQuest, 2020